Paul Nelson Raleigh, NC 27612

> Phone: 864-812-0123 | Email: pmnelso@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/paulmnelson1 Github: github.com/pmnelson89 | Portfolio: pmnelson89.github.io/portfolio/

Web Developer

Web developer with a creative personality and passion for problem solving. Experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Vue, and React. Strong communication developed during a successful career in sales during which account profits were grown 36%. Earned a bachelor's degree in Parks & Protected Areas Management from Clemson University and a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Motivated and prepared to collaborate with others to create innovative projects tailored to the unique needs of clients.

Technologies

HTML

CSS

JavaScript Node.js

Express Vue.js

React.js

JQuery

Firebase

MySQL

MongoDB

Projects

Project Name: On The Fly Staffing

Link to Github: github.com/pmnelson89/On-The-Fly-Staffing Link to Deployed Project: on-the-fly-staff.herokuapp.com

- A restaurant job service that allows candidates to submit an application which is then archived in a mongoDB database and available to search results by employers.
- Responsible for planning the dashboard functionality as well as overall design of the site.
- React.js, Material-UI, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Twilio, AuthO

Project Name: Clicky Game

Link to Github: github.com/pmnelson89/Clicky-Game Link to Deployment: pmnelson89.github.io/Clicky-Game

- This is a memory game that asks users to click on images of Formula 1 drivers. After a driver is selected, the images are shuffled for the next selection. The goal is not to select the same driver twice.
- React.js, JavaScript, Node.js, CSS

Project Name: Node SQL Storefront

Link to Github: github.com/pmnelson89/node-sql-storefront

- This app uses the Google Books API to search, display, and save books using a mongoDB database.
- JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL, Inquirer

Professional Experience

Nelson Staffing • 2019 - current

A recruiting and staffing company managing contract employees for Google Fiber.

GOOGLE FIBER BRAND AMBASSADOR

Utilized Door-to-Door sales tactics in order to bring Google Fiber directly to the customer and cultivate a strong sense of community around the product.

Key Accomplishments:

- Researched ISPs to stay knowledgeable about competing products and promotions.
- Strategically planned sales routes to maximize efficiency and effectiveness.
- Utilized technical knowledge of the product to demonstrate how switching to Google Fiber would be advantageous to potential customers.
- Proposed products and services based on the unique internet needs of customers.

V3 Lighting • 2018 - 2019

A manufacturer rep agency specializing in commercial and industrial LED applications.

DESIGN SALES

Prospected and developed business relationships with architects, interior designers, and electrical engineers. Assist in analyzing building plans and making lighting recommendations based on the unique needs of the architectural space. Key Accomplishments:

- Researched manufacturers and publications to stay up to date on trends in the lighting design industry.
- Utilized software to run photometric tests to plan lighting layouts and ensure adequate lumen output throughout architectural spaces.
- Proposed lighting packages based on the unique design goals, lighting effectiveness, and budget consciousness.

SOUTHEASTERN PAPER GROUP • 2015 - 2018

A distributor of disposables, packaging, and janitorial supplies and equipment.

SALES CONSULTANT

Developed and implemented sales and business development strategy in collaboration with senior colleagues, clients, and external stakeholders utilizing strong industry experience, technical capability, and excellent interpersonal skills.

Key Accomplishments:

- Guided and educated healthcare systems on ways to improve products and processes that impact facility management
 and challenges of the industry.
- Developed working relationships with managers and personnel from various departments, i.e., environmental services, infection prevention, and materials management.
- Provided a comprehensive analysis of customer processes to demonstrate how Southeastern Paper Group can streamline operations and deliver effective solutions.
- Reduced costs in product and labor while maintaining best safety practices.
- Grew profit to \$1.2m in sales in 2017, a 36% increase from the previous year.

Education & Training

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development
UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA CHAPEL HILL | Raleigh, NC

Bachelor of Science in Parks, Recreation & Tourism Management CLEMSON UNIVERSITY | Clemson, SC